Hey guys, welcome to another video, so we will see the CMD.exe, that was one of the
system general from binary, that was highly used by the detector foil, they are performing
some attacks like execution or executing the files and executing the file as malware since
the machine.
So, if you check the log in for CMD.exe, it will be used for a different purpose, it
was used for a different purpose, I already said it is like executing something and we
can do a lot of things, so we can execute that file installation and if you want to download
any file from the server, you can go ahead and you can do that, if you want to upload anything
you can go ahead and do that, so there is not a lot of users for a CMD.exe, so let's
speak a simple example, I just have one of some malware called the mal CMD, it is an
executable file, anyways, if you see this is the application.exe file, so if I need to
execute this file, I can do it with the CMD.exe, so you can see here, so if I give mal CMD,
so now you can see there is no Windows PowerShell get executed and it can be loaded, so now
you can see I got a session for a machine, so this is the one, so don't worry about this
console, this is one of the C2 frame of call does a startler, so we will see the scene opening
session, so don't worry about that, we already said this was the CVD.exe, when I execute
the dead shell, so it opened us PowerShell, so we got a session, so you can perform another
attacks, other attacks from here, so we can see everything after that, but we will discuss
more about the CMD.exe, so also if you need to perform, if you need to execute some file
as mal var and for the machine, you can go ahead and you can do that, so that will be
easy, you have to just open the server, let's create one of the file, so this is called
as the file is mal var, I just created one of the file and I will be saving this server,
file, so there is no file for this mal var, we need to execute it manually by the process
of file, by using the process of CMD.exe or PowerShell.exe, so let's open the machine
and we will download the file, let me copy this and I will execute in the CMD.exe, so
I will execute from here, let me see what happened after we have executed, so now the shell
has been terminated and we will take our star cooler, so now you can see another one,
session has been opened, so this is called as a file as mal var, so we can do a lot and
a lot of things in the CMD.exe, so today we have seen in the law there, so it has been
used, so don't worry about the alternate data streams and we will cover the things in
a permissions, also you can able to execute the dot that files, so if you have a dot that
mal var, so already you know our VM machine fee executed a lot of that files, so this is
a bad file, so disabled, disabling Windows Defender, for Windows 10, if I go for a property,
so you can see this is a bad file, you can execute any files in CMD.exe, okay, not only
execute and you can do a lot of things, so that is thing, we will help us this video and
we will continue our discussion in the next video, see you guys, bye bye.